Nikita Verma

Software Engineer

+91-7017853934 | nikitaverma102001@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/nikita-verma-5066b51b3/ | github.com/nikita10110

Summary

I am qualified and professional backend developer with two years of experience in creating, enhancing, maintaining, testing, and debugging backend application. I possess strong creative and analytical skills and am seeking an engaging role within a respected organization to expand my learning, knowledge, and skills while making a significant contribution to the success of the company. I am passionate about learning new technologies and driving innovation in software development.

EXPERIENCE

PAYTM(One97 Communication)

July 2022- Present

Software Engineer(Backend Developer)

Remote

- Worked on developing multiple microservcies to integrate Open network for Digital Commerce(ONDC) in paytm app. Java
- Buliding scalable system to handle large traffic to provide seamless customer experience.
- Having the responsibility of desgining, solutioning, development and deployment of various ONDC features.
- Developed Tracking api's that resulted in a **60 percent** increase in trackable orders placed by customers, enchancing the overall customer experience and order management process . **Java, Mysql**
- Worked on multiple services which take cares of order placement and logistics. Java, Mysql, Kafka, Redis
- Knowledge of automated build/continuous delivery, experience of **Jenkins**, deployment.
- Maintained and worked on Panel for merchant finances and business purpose.
- Setup and fixed whole new legacy system from scratch and migrated to other entity of organisation knowing whole microservices architecture and setup end to end pipeline. **NodeJs**
- Successfully migrated 9.18 Lac user data for KYC system of Paytm Money using batch processing techniques and Python scripts, orchestrated through Rundeck automation platform, achieving a flawless 100 percent success rate.
- Designed and implemented a seamless User Onboarding Journey system for Paytm Money, streamlining the process and enhancing user experience. Java, Mysql

PAYTM(One97 Communication)

Jan 2022 – July 2022

Software Engineer Intern

Remote

- Involved in writing test case for various services along with developing using Junit, Mockito.
- Also performed various deployment and maintenance of projects on **Jenkins**.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C

Technologies/Frameworks: SpringBoot, Kafka, NodeJs, SQL, RabbitMQ, Github, Rundeck, Jenkins, ElasticSearch,

MicroServices, Machine Learning

Developer Tools: Git, Gitlab, VS Code, Postman, Intellij, Jira, Bitbucket, Google Colab, Jupyter

General: Data Structure, OOPS, DBMS

EDUCATION

Dr A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University Bachelor of Technology(B.Tech) - Computer Science and Engineering: CGPA: 8.04 Meerut Public Girl's School Intermediate: Central Board of Secondary Education: Percentage: 90.80 July 2018 - June 2022 Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh Meerut, Uttar Pradesh

Meerut Public Girl's School

High School: Central Board of Secondary Education: CGPA: 8.6 Meerut, Uttar Pradesh

PROJECTS

Face recognition using Facenet | Python, ML

• My project recognizes the face in the image, categorizes the per-son(name) using the InceptionResnet model.

Password Strength Analyzer | Python, ML, NLP

• Identify if the password is of weak, strong or intermediate strength using various NLP techniques and classification model on tokenized data.

Quiz Backend Application | Java, SpringBoot, Mysql, Postman

• This application provides backend services which allows to manage quizzes, questions, and user responses.